Kirill Tolmachev

Senior C# developer Tbilisi, Georgia/Yerevan, Armenia +995-5910-947-46 +374-41-132-138 tolmachev.kirill.a@gmail.com

About me

I am a highly motivated and experienced IT professional with over 10 years of experience in the industry, specifically in development of C#/.NET applications and web services. I have a strong educational background, having graduated from the Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology (MIPT) with a MA in Applied Mathematics and Computer Science. I have a deep understanding and extensive knowledge of technical skills and am seeking an opportunity to utilize my skills and abilities in a role that offers professional growth within a resourceful, innovative and flexible work environment.

I do not support aggression against Ukraine which is why I have chosen to reside and work in Armenia. I have set up a company in Armenia where I am the sole employee, which allows me to work internationally without any need for communication with Russian authorities.

Education

Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology (MIPT)

MA in Applied Mathematics and Computer Science

Skills

Strong expertise in C#, .NET/.NET Core/.NET Framework, ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET MVC, NHibernate, EntityFramework, REST/GraphQL, T-SQL, NoSQL, Git, LINQ, OpenAPI (Swagger), WCF, WPF, WinForms, DDD, MSSQL, SQLite, NUnit, GitHub Actions, MSMQ, OOP, OOD, Unity3D.

Experience with AWS, Azure, Docker, Kubernetes, Redis, RabbitMQ, HTML 5, CSS, TypeScript, JavaScript, React.JS, Vue.JS, Pixi.JS, jQuery, MatLab, PostgreSQL, C++, Qt.

Professional Experience:

2019-till now - Senior C# Developer at Dynata LLC

Main responsibilities and achievements:

- Led the development of an ASP.NET Core REST API application which was then used by major clients such as Netflix, PepsiCo etc.
- Developed functionality to synchronize datasets with external data sources, including huge datasets with millions of records. My optimizations reduced transfer and processing time by over 33% on average and in certain cases - by over 50%.

- Created an extendible expression evaluation framework to support a SaaS data analysis and visualization solution. This framework provided exceptional results being used in 4 major product features and required near zero maintenance time.
- Designed and implemented processing mechanisms for new proprietary data formats, parsing complex user-defined logical and mathematical expressions, and data validation.
- Contributed to the design of new features by identifying and outlining feature requirements.
- Increased unit test code coverage by 15%

2016-2019 - Senior C# Developer at MarketSight LLC

Main responsibilities and achievements:

- Provided major code refactoring which reduced code coupling by over 30% in critical areas.
- Implemented processing algorithms for 2 proprietary data formats and 4 external data formats such as SPSS, SAS, SSS.
- Implemented REST API support in an existing data visualization application which enabled third party application support for the existing code base.
- Developed functionality for data processing, including designing and implementing processing mechanisms for new proprietary data formats.
- Identified and fixed 2 major security vulnerabilities.
- Developed frontend modules and web pages for data synchronization management, data visualization and administration features.
- Collaborated with 4 different cross-functional teams to provide efficient integration of MarketSight with related data providers and visualization solutions.

2014 - 2016 - Development Team Lead at DAFE Engineering

Main responsibilities and achievements:

- Led the development of a backend for a mobile aeronavigation system, resulting in successful contract execution with 2 data providers, several rounds of investments and an acquisition of a patent.
- Led the development of an automated pilot stand operator workplace from scratch.
- Worked directly with the company's biggest client, participated in requirements outlining and managed a team of 8 people while still being actively involved in development.
- Contributed to the development and support of various project related to data processing and visualization.

2012 – 2014 – C#/C++ Developer at DAFE Engineering

Worked on multiple projects:

- Developed backend for a mobile aeronavigation system.
- Contributed to the development of a frontend for a mobile aeronavigation system (C++, Qt). Designed data storage formats which reduced data processing time by over 80%.

- Provided development and support for multiple pilot stands, including visualization systems and sensor signal processing (C#, C++, MatLab, Unity3D).
- Contributed to the development and support of an experimental automated flight assistance system (C++, Qt).

2011 – Developed a simple CRM system for a local taxi company, WinForms/MSSQL-based (used for a couple of years before switching to Uber).

Personal Projects:

- Developed multiple bots and Unity3D games.
- Participated in numerous game jams.
- Currently developing a tycoon game with Unity3D (3D, Ui Toolkit, USS).

Languages:

Russian - fluent

English - advanced

Spanish – beginner